Guide to the H.N. Tiemann & Co. Photograph Collection [1880-1916] PR 129
New-York Historical Society
H.N. Tiemann & Co. Photograph Collection
[1880-1916]
New-York Historical Society
H.N. Tiemann & Co.
PR 129
3.75 Linear feet (10 boxes)
This collection of negatives from the commercial photography company H.N. Tiemann & Co. documents Manhattan buildings, bridges, churches, hotels, prominent residences, and civic events from ca. 1880 through 1916. Copy negatives of other photographers' works are included. The H.N. Tiemann & Co. Photograph Collection is digitized and available in the Shelby White and Leon Levy Digital Library.
Provenance
Purchase, 1952.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to 30 photocopies per day per person. Suitability of the original for photocopying is at the discretion of the staff. Neither blueprints nor tracings can be copied under any circumstances. Duplication of large-format items will be done by the house photographer. See Print Room guidelines for details.
Biographical Note
H.N. Tiemann & Co. was a Manhattan-based commercial photography company which primarily recorded prominent New York buildings, bridges, civic celebrations, and fashionable street scenes for publication or general sale beginning in the 1890s.
Hermann Newell Tiemann (1863-1957), founder and president of H.N. Tiemann & Co., was born in New York on February 2, 1863. His father, Julius William Tiemann, was the brother of New York City Mayor Daniel F. Tiemann and a partner in D.F. Tiemann & Co. paint manufacturers in Manhattanville. His mother was Julius Tiemann's second wife, Marie Antoinette Megie of Brooklyn. Hermann Tiemann married Belle Louise Minor in her hometown of Newtown, Connecticut on June 22 1892. He lived with his family in Connecticut from 1905 until his death in 1957, although his business remained in New York City through 1948. His name is often misspelled as "Herman", without the final "n", in city directories and other publications.
Trow's New York City Directory of 1891 lists Hermann Tiemann as a commercial photographer, but he was already active as an amateur by 1885 when he showed his work in the First Annual Exhibition of the Society of Amateur Photographers of New York. Tiemann continued to exhibit through the Society of Amateur Photographers of New York and then as a member of the Camera Club of New York throughout the 1880s and 1890s.
Tiemann's first studio opened at 13 West 42nd Street in Manhattan; it moved to number 19 and then 17 West 42nd Street between 1893 and 1898. From 1904 to 1919, H.N. Tiemann & Co. was located at 4 East 30th Street, moving in 1920 to 176 Lexington Avenue where it remained until 1948, the year of the firm's presumed dissolution (when the firm ceased appearing in directories). Beginnning 1920, directories list the firm as a purveyor of photographic supplies. Hermann Tiemann died in Connecticut in 1957 at the age of 94.
Scope and Content Note
The H.N. Tiemann & Co. Photograph Collection spans the period from ca. 1880 to 1916 and contains 283 black and white negatives (measuring 8 x 10 inches) of views of prominent Manhattan locations. Most negatives are glass, but a few film negatives are included. Negatives are filed by Tiemann's stock numbers. The collection was purchased as a discrete group of 480 negatives in 1952 and was originally integrated into the Negative File (PR 045). Some of the negatives were filed without indication of their creator and remain in the Negative File. Gaps in the numbering sequence reflect the existence of those negatives. Some of the images in this collection were cataloged individually for inclusion in the department's in-house card catalog; they were originally assigned numbers consisting of the prefix 63200- followed by the Tiemann stock number. Most negatives bear Tiemann's imprint, "THE H.N. TIEMANN CO. NEW YORK CITY" or are marked with the firm's distinctive numbering. Titles in this finding aid represent the captions which were handwritten or stamped onto the negatives with abbreviations left intact; titles in brackets have been supplied by N-YHS staff. Dates reflect Tiemann's as they are written on the negatives; dates in brackets have been provided by N-YHS staff.
Negatives in this collection portray Manhattan streets, buildings, hotels, churches, residences and landmarks. Most views are of prominent locations, tourist attractions, grand architecture, or fashionable street views. However, some photographs of shanties show a less glamorous Manhattan at the turn of the 20th Century. Among heavily represented subjects are the 1909 Hudson-Fulton Celebration, Queensboro Bridge, Croton Reservoir, Fifth Avenue, the Flatiron Building, the American Museum of Natural History, Grand Central Terminal, Madison Square Garden and Union Square. Photographs of residences include those of notable New Yorkers A.T. Stewart, Harry F. Sinclair, Cornelius Vanderbilt, and Gouverneur Morris, Jr. A few photographs depict scenes outside of New York City, including one copy negative of a photograph of the United States Capitol in Washington, D.C. and a view of a military camp in Peekskill, New York.
Included in the collection are numerous copy negatives of engravings, lithographs, and photographs by other artists, many of which depict earlier views of Manhattan. Copies of photographs by Irving Underhill, J.S. Johnston, and Joseph Hall are present in the collection; most original photographers represented have not been identified. Copy negatives of lithographs by W.C. Rogers & Co. and G. Hayward are included.
Arrangement
Materials have been arranged by Tiemann's original stock numbers; unidentified negatives have been placed at the end.
Related Material at The New-York Historical Society
This collection was originally integrated into the Negative File (PR 045); some negatives were filed without reference to Tiemann as the photographer and remain in the Negative File. Vintage prints by H.N. Tiemann & Co., received from a variety of sources, can be found in the Geographic File (PR 020). The Album File includes an album of Tiemann's photographs of the unveiling of the monument marking the site of Fort Washington in 1901 (PR 002-58) as well as an album of photographs of old New York which includes 50 photographs by Tiemann (PR 002-345).
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital copies are available in the Shelby White and Leon Levy Digital Library.
Church buildings -- New York (State) -- New York -- Pictorial works.; negatives (photographs); Queensboro Bridge (New York, N.Y.); Croton Reservoir (New York, N.Y.); Hudson-Fulton Celebration, 1909.; Manhattan (New York, N.Y.) -- Buildings, structures, etc. -- Pictorial works.; Hotels -- New York (State) -- New York -- Pictorial works.; Historic buildings -- New York (State) -- New York -- Pictorial works.; American Museum of Natural History; Flatiron Building (New York, N.Y.)
- unspecified
  - New York City College Ams. Ave. 139 St., 1910 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - New York City College, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - New York City College, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - [Harlem] Speedway and Washington Bridge, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American Flag at Washington Bridge, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - [Harlem] Speedway at High Bridge, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Queens Borough Bridge [Queensboro Bridge], 1910 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Queens Borough Bridge [Queensboro Bridge], 1910 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - [American] Museum of Natural History, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Soldiers and Sailors Monument, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - City Hall Building, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Hudson-Fulton Celebration Plaza Hotel, 1909 Sept. 27 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hudson-Fulton Court of Honor Celebration, 1909 Sept. 26 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Washington Arch Hudson-Fulton Celebration. N.Y., 1909 Sept. 26 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Morgan Building, Wall St. [decorated with flags], 1909 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Madison Square Garden [Copy negative of photograph by unidentified photographer], 1909 (Box 1, Folder 16a)
  - Looking up Wall St. [Looking west from Nassau Street], 1909 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - New Theatre 62-63rd Streets Central Park West [Later called Century Theatre], [1909] (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Interior - 5 Ave. Presbyterian Church, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Cooper Union, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Looking up Wall St. [Looking west toward Trinity Church], 1909 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Flatiron Building, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Queens Borough Bridge [Queensboro Bridge], 1909 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Morgan Library, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Pabst Building, 1900 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Murray Hill Hotel, Park Ave., N.Y., 1893 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - [Westminster Hotel, Irving Place, and 18th Street], [1909] (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - [Fifth Avenue and 34th Street, showing Astor and A.T. Stewart Residences], undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - The Dewitt Clinton Locomotive and Train, 1893 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - [St. Luke's Hospital, Fifth Avenue and 54th Street], 1894 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - [West End Avenue, 80th-81st Streets], 1894 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - [Washington Irving House, Irving Place and 17th Street], [1900] (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - [National Academy of Design], undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - [American Museum of Natural History], [1890] (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - The Old Church of St. Ignatius, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Grand Central Depot, 42nd Street, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - [A.T. Stewart Residence, Fifth Avenue and 34th Street], undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Windsor Hotel 5th Ave., N.Y. [Copy negative of photograph by J.S. Johnston, ca. 1885], undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - [30th Street between Fifth and Madison Avenues], [1909] (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Gilsey House. Photo of Hotel at Broadway and 29th St., 1904 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - [Sheep in Sheep's Meadow, Central Park], undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - [Bethesda Fountain, Central Park], 1896 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - [View along the Mall, Central Park], 1896 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - [High Bridge and the Speedway, Highbridge Park at 174th Street, also showing Kyle's Park Dance Park], undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Rectory of Grace Church, Broadway and 11th Street, undated (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - [Soldiers and Sailors Monument, Riverside Drive and West 89th Street, built 1902], undated (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - [Columbus Circle and Merchant's Café at Central Park], undated (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - [American Museum of Natural History], [1895] (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - [Statue of J. Marion Sims, M.D., Sixth Avenue and 42nd Street], 1894 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - [Washington Arch, Washington Square Park], undated (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - N.Y. Herald Building, Herald Square, N.Y., 1894 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - [Custom House, Bowling Green], [1909] (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - [City Hall and City Hall Park, draped with flags for the Dewey Celebration], [1899] (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - [Interior of City College], undated (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - [Presbyterian Hospital, Madison Avenue and 70th Street], [1909] (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - [Presbyterian Hospital, Madison Avenue and 70th Street from Park Avenue], [1909] (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - [Majestic Hotel, Central Park West and 72nd Street], 1899 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - [Fourth Presbyterian Church, West End Avenue and 91st Street], 1896 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - [New York Harbor], undated (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Library Building, Columbia University, N.Y. [Low Library], undated (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - [Cornelius Vanderbilt House, Fifth Avenue and 57th Street], 1894 (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - [Wall Street, looking west toward Trinity Church], [1909] (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - [Fourth Avenue, east side near 26th Street, with views of Hotel Putnam and Hotel Preston], [1905] (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - [Dr. J. Peters House, Broadway and 98th Street], 1897 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - [Hotel Meurice, Fifth Avenue and 42nd Street], [1893] (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - [Panorama view, from 27th to 28th Streets, from Park Avenue?], undated (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - [Windsor Arcade, Fifth Avenue, 46th and 47th Streets], undated (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - [Old Shot Tower, Worth Street], [1909] (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - [University Club, Fifth Avenue and 54th Street, with view of the Gotham Hotel under construction], [1905] (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - [Shanty Town], 1894 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - [New York University Building, Washington Square East], 1894 Mar. (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Looking north on 5th Ave. from 34th St., [1899] (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - The English Locomotive "Queen-Empress", 1893 (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Columbia University Club, 44 West 36th St., undated (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - [Leake and] Watt's Orphan Asylum, Cathedral Heights, 1892 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Old Reservoir, 40-42 Sts. N.Y. showing interior, 1893 (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Old Reservoir, 40-42 Sts. & 5 Ave., 1893 (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - [Fifth Avenue, looking south from 42nd Street, showing the reservoir], 1899 (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Old 7 & 69th Regiment Armory Cooper Square, 1908 (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Columbia University Club [15 Madison Square], 1905 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - [Columbia University Club, 15 Madison Square], 1905 (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Old Dutch Windmill, 1889 (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - New York University [former building demolished in 1894] (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - [New York University, former building demolished in 1894] (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - Astor Residence, 34 St. & 5 Ave., 1898 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - Amsterdam Ave. at 100 Street [Shanties], 1894 (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - Amsterdam Avenue 100 Street, 1894 (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - Grant's Tomb, 1894 (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - General Sherman's Monument, 1894 (Box 4, Folder 119)
  - Front of the "Dewey Arch," N.Y., 1899 (Box 4, Folder 120)
  - [Richard Morris Hunt Memorial, Fifth Avenue at 70th Street], [1905] (Box 4, Folder 121)
  - Methodist Church, Broadway at 67 St., undated (Box 4, Folder 122)
  - Supreme Court 25th St. Madison Ave., 1907 (Box 4, Folder 123-126)
  - Night Illum. Of English and White Squadron, 1898 (Box 4, Folder 127)
  - Queens Borough Bridge N.Y. side [Queensboro Bridge], 1909 (Box 4, Folder 128)
  - Church of the Transfiguration E. 29th St., 1909 (Box 4, Folder 129)
  - Dr. Parkhurst's Church 24 Mad. Ave. [Madison Square Presbyterian Church], 1899 (Box 4, Folder 130)
  - Morris House, Front View N.W. [Port Morris, Bronx], 1905 (Box 4, Folder 131)
  - Morris House, Back View, 1905 (Box 4, Folder 132)
  - Interior of Grant's Tomb, 1896 (Box 4, Folder 133)
  - [Residence of Gouverneur Morris, 132nd Street, Port Morris, Bronx], [1905] (Box 4, Folder 134)
  - [Entrance of St. Luke's Hospital, Fifth Avenue and 54th Street], [1894] (Box 4, Folder 135)
  - [Residence of Gouverneur Morris, 132nd Street, Port Morris, Bronx], [1905] (Box 4, Folder 136)
  - [Federal Hall, 28 Wall Street, corner of Nassau], [1909] (Box 4, Folder 138)
  - [Interior of Grace Church, Broadway and 10th Street], undated (Box 4, Folder 139)
  - [General Joe Wheeler], undated (Box 4, Folder 140)
  - [After the fire at Park Avenue and 42nd Street], [1895-1896] (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - [James Madison, copy negative of painting by Asher B. Durand], [1905] (Box 4, Folder 142)
  - [Trees in Central Park], undated (Box 5, Folder 143)
  - Essex Street Court House, Ludlow Street, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 144)
  - [Rudd Mansion, Riverside Drive at 114th Street], 1911 (Box 5, Folder 147)
  - National Art Club, Gramercy Park, undated (Box 5, Folder 148)
  - Regiment Armory 94-95 St., Park Ave., 1893 (Box 5, Folder 149)
  - 30th St. Between 4th and Madison Ave., 1912 (Box 5, Folder 150)
  - Magdelen House, undated (Box 5, Folder 152)
  - View from Morningside Park, undated (Box 5, Folder 154)
  - West Presbyterian Church interior 42 St. between 5 & 6 Ave., 1911 (Box 5, Folder 157)
  - Row of houses on Lafayette St., 1911 (Box 5, Folder 160)
  - Fifth Ave. at 53rd St., 1911 (Box 5, Folder 162)
  - Colony Club [120 Madison Avenue], 1905 (Box 5, Folder 164)
  - Church of Transfiguration, East 29 St., 1911 (Box 5, Folder 165)
  - Soldiers and Sailors Monument, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 167)
  - New York Public Library, 5 Ave. at 40 St., 1911 (Box 5, Folder 168)
  - Metropolitan Tower, Mad. Ave. at 23 St., 1911 (Box 5, Folder 170)
  - Pennsylvania R.R. Station 7 Ave. at 32 St., 1911 (Box 5, Folder 171)
  - Daly's Theatre, 31 St. and Broadway, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 172)
  - Holland House, 5 Ave. at 30 St., 1911 (Box 5, Folder 173)
  - New York Public Library, 5 Ave. at 40-42 St., 1911 (Box 5, Folder 175)
  - Night Illumination St. Patrick's Cathedral, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 176)
  - Madison Square Garden, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 177)
  - Hudson River Looking north from 77 St., 1912 (Box 5, Folder 178)
  - Madison Square Garden, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 179)
  - Astor House [Broadway between Vesey and Barclay Streets], 1913 (Box 5, Folder 183)
  - Astor House [Broadway between Vesey and Barclay Streets], 1913 (Box 5, Folder 185)
  - Fraunces Tavern, 1913 (Box 5, Folder 186)
  - 4 Ave. from Union Sq., 1905 (Box 5, Folder 194)
  - Grand Union Hotel, Park Ave. at 42 Street, 1913 (Box 5, Folder 195)
  - 30 St. between 2 & 3 Ave. [Adams Memorial Church], 1913 (Box 5, Folder 196)
  - 5 Ave. at 47 St., 1902 (Box 6, Folder 197)
  - Union Square [Horse-drawn fire apparatus in parade of firemen], 1908 (Box 6, Folder 198)
  - Lying in Hospital, 2 Ave. at 18 Street, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 202)
  - St. Bartholomew Church, Mad. Ave. and 34 St., 1914 (Box 6, Folder 203)
  - 5 Ave. at 40 St., 1913 (Box 6, Folder 204)
  - Dynt House, 18 Leroy St., 1913 (Box 6, Folder 205)
  - Knox Building, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 207)
  - [Fifth Avenue north from 53rd Street, showing St. Luke's Church, copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer, 1898], 1914 (Box 6, Folder 209)
  - 5 Ave. 40-41 St., 1914 (Box 6, Folder 210)
  - Old City College 23 St. 4 Ave., 1914 (Box 6, Folder 215)
  - Washington Market, Vesey & West St., 1914 (Box 6, Folder 216)
  - [Broadway from Bowling Green to Morris Street], [1914] (Box 6, Folder 240)
  - St. Ignatius Church, 56 West 40 St. [Interior], 1896 (Box 6, Folder 243)
  - Bway [Broadway] north from 37 Street, [1915] (Box 6, Folder 247)
  - Bway [Broadway] No. from 30 Street, 1915 (Box 6, Folder 248)
  - Admiral Farragut Statue [Madison Square Park], 1913 (Box 6, Folder 251)
  - 4 Avenue - 28 St., 1911 (Box 6, Folder 252)
  - Hudson River north from 78th St., 1909 (Box 6, Folder 254)
  - Broadway south from 60 Street, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 255)
  - Bridge at Broadway & Fulton St. [Loew's Bridge, copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer, 1868], undated (Box 6, Folder 257)
  - Park Row [north from Frankfort Street, copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer, 1878], undated (Box 6, Folder 259)
  - [South from 18th Street, Chickering Hall, copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer, 1879], undated (Box 6, Folder 262)
  - Equitable Life Building B'way [Broadway] & Cedar [Photograph of drawing by an unidentified artist], undated (Box 6, Folder 267)
  - The New York Herald, Broadway, Ann St. [copy negative of a lithograph by W.C. Rogers & Co. published in Jos. Shannon's Manual, 1868], undated (Box 6, Folder 268)
  - Broadway Central Hotel [copy negative of a lithograph by an unidentified artist], undated (Box 6, Folder 269)
  - East side of Broadway [between] 37-38 St., 1911 (Box 6, Folder 277)
  - Abermale-Hoffman House, Bway and 24 St. [copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer], undated (Box 6, Folder 278)
  - Maine Memorial, Central Park, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 280)
  - Eden's Museum [identical to 431], 1915 (Box 6, Folder 287)
  - [Masonic Temple, Sixth Avenue and 23rd Street, copy negative of a stereo view by an unidentified photographer], undated (Box 6, Folder 290)
  - Abermale-Hoffman House, Broadway and 24th Street, copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer, 1911], undated (Box 6, Folder 293)
  - St. Patrick's [Cathedral], 1915 (Box 6, Folder 295)
  - Union Club [Fifth Avenue and 21st Street], [1880] (Box 7, Folder 296)
  - Broadway and 8 Street [copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer, ca. 1895], undated (Box 7, Folder 297)
  - Broadway and 10 St. [Copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer, ca. 1895], undated (Box 7, Folder 298)
  - Broadway North from Rector Street [Copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer, ca. 1885], undated (Box 7, Folder 300)
  - 4 Ave. and 23 Street [Copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer, ca. 1910], undated (Box 7, Folder 301)
  - Broadway and Astor Pl. [Sinclair House], 1895 (Box 7, Folder 303)
  - Broadway and 23 Street, 1895 (Box 7, Folder 304)
  - Broadway and 8 Street [Copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer], undated (Box 7, Folder 305)
  - Madison Ave. No. 42nd St. [Dr. Tynge's Church], undated (Box 7, Folder 309)
  - [Four exposures of a Beal Panorama view of Manhattan from the Brooklyn Bridge, copy negative of original], undated (Box 7, Folder 311a-d)
  - #1 State St. Home of R. Fulton, 1889 (Box 7, Folder 313)
  - [Metropolitan Hotel, Broadway and Prince Street, copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer, ca. 1880], undated (Box 7, Folder 314)
  - Brewster & Co. of Broome Street [Copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer, ca. 1885?], undated (Box 7, Folder 315)
  - Delmonicos, 14 Streeet and 5 Ave. [Copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer], undated (Box 7, Folder 316)
  - [Franklin House, copy negative of a lithograph by an unidentified lithographer], undated (Box 7, Folder 317)
  - [Erickson House, 36 Beech Street, copy negative of a photograph by Irving Underhill, ca. 1913], undated (Box 7, Folder 319)
  - Dr. Parkhurst's Old Church [Madison Square Presbyterian Church, copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer], undated (Box 7, Folder 320)
  - Sugar House, 40 Rose St., 1895? (Box 7, Folder 322)
  - 5 Ave. & 41 Street [Copy negative of a photograph by Wurts Brothers, 1895], undated (Box 7, Folder 323)
  - St. Esprit Church [East 27th Street], 1916 (Box 7, Folder 324)
  - Old Pres. Church, 11 St. & 7 Ave., 1916 (Box 7, Folder 325)
  - Grand Central Station West [Copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer, ca. 1880], undated (Box 7, Folder 326)
  - New York Central Station W. Broadway & Liberty, undated (Box 7, Folder 327)
  - St. Thomas Church [Fifth Avenue looking south from 54th Street, copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer, ca. 1871], undated (Box 7, Folder 330)
  - Park Ave. & 34 St. "Messiah" [Church of the Messiah, copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer, 1871], undated (Box 7, Folder 330)
  - St. Thomas Church [Fifth Avenue looking south from 54th Street, copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer, ca. 1876], undated (Box 7, Folder 333)
  - Masonic Temple[Sixth Avenue and 23rd Street, copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer, ca. 1873], undated (Box 7, Folder 334)
  - Broadway north from Pine Street [Copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer, ca. 1873], undated (Box 7, Folder 337)
  - Dr. Hall's Church [Old South Dutch Reformed Church, copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer], undated (Box 7, Folder 342)
  - Old Sky Line, 1 Broadway, 1885 (Box 7, Folder 348)
  - Coenhe's Shop, Jeanette Park [Copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer], undated (Box 7, Folder 354)
  - Union League Club [Copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer, ca. 1885], undated (Box 8, Folder 361)
  - 7th Regiment on Riverside Drive [Copy negative of a photograph by an unidentified photographer, 1862], undated (Box 8, Folder 362)